Guide to the ILGWU. Local 89. Luigi Antonini correspondence, 1919-1968
ILGWU. Local 89. Luigi Antonini correspondence,
- Series II. Correspondence, 1933-1965.
  - Foreign, Italy. Requests and remittances., 1955 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Foreign, Italy. Requests and remittances., 1956 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Foreign, Italy. Requests and remittances., 1957 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Foreign, Italy. Requests and remittances., 1957 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Foreign, Italy. Requests and remittances., 1958 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Foreign, Italy. Requests and remittances., 1958 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Foreign, Italy. Requests and remittances., 1959-1960 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Foreign, Italy. Requests and remittances., 1961-1962 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Foreign, Italy. Requests and remittances., 1963 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Foreign, Italy. Requests and remittances., 1964 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Foreign, Mexico, Soviet Union, Switzerland., 1936-1946 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Four Freedoms Award. Presented to Francis Biddle., 1943 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    April 1943. Includes letter. from Pres. Franklin D. Roosevelt.
  - Four Freedoms Award. Presented to Gen. Mark with Clark., 1945 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    Oct. 1945.
  - Four Freedoms Award. Presented to William Green., 1951 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    Dec. 1951. Includes Harry Truman ltr.
  - Four Freedoms Award. Presented to George Meany., 1957 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    Dec. 1957.
  - Four Freedoms Award. Presented to Harry S. Truman., 1959 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    Dec. 1959. Includes Truman ltrs.
  - Four Freedoms Award. Presented to David Dubinsky., 1961 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    Dec. 1961. Includes John F. Kennedy ltr.
  - Four Freedoms Foundation., 1950-1961 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - The Free China Fund for Medical and Refugee Aid., 1955-1961 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Free Trade Union Committee., 1948-1964 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    I.c.w. Jay Lovestone and Irving Brown on Italian politics.
  - Free Trade Union Movement in Italy., 1949 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    Includes ltr. from Vasco Cesari to Jay Lovestone on attempt to build in Italy a free trade union movement warning against splitting with Communists without preparation, June 1949.
  - Friends of the Garibaldi Brigade., 1939 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    Includes financial requests from Humberto Galleani.
  - Frigenti, Frank. Deportation case., 1941-1943 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - G: Gen. Correspondence., 1940-1951 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - G: Gen. Correspondence., 1952-1964 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Galati, Victor (Dr.). Reports on local members' health service problems., 1959-1960 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Gelo, John. Correspondence, 1949-1960 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Gelo, John: Jan. 1957. Correspondence. (Box 24, Folder 10)
    ltr. of condolences on Gelo's death.
  - Ghiringhelli, Antonio (Dr.)., 1950-1953 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Giovannitti, Arturo., 1938-1958 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - H: Gen. Correspondence., 1948-1965 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Health Insurance and Health and Welfare Funds in the Dress Industry., 1944-1957 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - High School of Fashion Industries (Central High School of Needle Trades)., 1949-1961 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - I., 1936-1951 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    Includes Correspondence and constitution of Italian Labor Confederation of Workers, Confederazione Sindacale Italiana del Lavoratori (CSIL).
  - I: Gen. Correspondence., 1952-1964 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Il Mattino D'ltalia., 1951-1955 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Immigration., 1939-1955 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    Includes cases and Correspondence on proposed McCarran Act to limit immigration.
  - Impellitteri, Vincent R. (Mayor, City of New York)., 1951-1952 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Infantile Paralysis (March of Dimes)., 1938-1964 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    Correspondence on Local campaign contributions.
  - Inter-American Association for Democracy and Freedom., 1955-1959 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, General Office Correspondence., 1939-1943 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    Includes Correspondence with David Dubinsky and Frederick F. Umhey.
  - ILGWU, General Office Correspondence., 1948-1964 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - ILGWU, Convention., 1959 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - ILGWU, Death Benefit Fund., 1950-1951 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - ILGWU, Education Dept., 1939-1961 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    Correspondence with Mark Starr and Fannia M. Cohn.
  - ILGWU, General Executive Board., 1953 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    Includes proposed constitutional changes from Committee on Constitutional Revision.
  - ILGWU, Political Dept., 1947-1961 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    Correspondence with Gus Tyler.
  - ILGWU, Union Health Center, 1936-1952 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - ILGWU, Unity House, 1939-195. (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Invitations to attend, sponsor or contribute to affairs, 1939 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Invitations, 1940-1941. (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Invitations, 1942-1943. (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Invitations, 1947-1948. (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Invitations, 1949 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Invitations, 1950-1953. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Invitations, 1954-1957. (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Invitations, 1958-1965. (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Irpinia, Avellino, Antonini's Hometown, 1948-1949. (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Israel, 1957 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Italia Libre, Argentina, 1942-1948. (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Italian American Labor Council. Misc., 1942 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Italian Center for Social Solidarity (Centro Italiano Solidarieta Sociale, Rome), 1953-1955. (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Italian Colonial Possessions in Africa (post-World War II)., 1948 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    Includes statement by IALC on disposal of former colonies.
  - Italian Committee for the Defense of Immigrants., 1938-1940 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Italian Confederation of Workers Unions, Confederazione Italiana Sindacati Lavoratori, (CISL)., 1947-1964 (Box 28)
    Includes Correspondence with Vasco Cesari, Giovanni Canini, Guido Cocchia, Roberto Cuzzanti and Bruno Storti on Italian labor and political activities. Correspondence with Giulio Pastore is filed separately under Pastore.
  - C.I.S.L., 1947-1949 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    Mostly ltrs. from Guido Cocchia.
  - C.I.S.L., 1950-1951. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - C.I.S.L., 1952-1953. (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - C.I.S.L., 1954-1957. (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - C.I.S.L., 1958-1959 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    1958-June 1959.
  - C.I.S.L., 1959-1961 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    July 1959-61.
  - C.I.S.L. Contributions., 1958-1960 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    Contributions to individual appeals through special CISL fund.
  - C.I.S.L. Contributions (cont.)., 1961-1964 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Italian General Confederation of Labor (Confederazione Generale Italiana del Lavoro, C.G.I.L.)., 1945-1959 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Italian Consulate. I.c.w. Luigi Nardi, Aldo Mazio, Carlo de Ferrariis Salzano., 1946-1957 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Italian-Cuban Democratic Association., 1948 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Italian Embassy. I.c.w. Alberto Tarchiani., 1945-1954 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Italian Federation of Clothing Workers (Federazione Unitaria Italiana Lavoratori Abbigliamento, F.U.I.L.A.)., 1950-1956 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Italian Hospital., 1936-1961 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Italian Republican Party (Partito Republicano Italiano). (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Italian Welfare League, Inc., 1939-1941 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Italiani Nel Mondo., 1947-1955 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    Correspondence with Leonida Felletti.
  - "Italy Today" Fair., 1952-1953 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - J: Gen. Correspondence., 1940-1961 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Jewish Labor Committee: 1945-55. (Box 29, Folder 11)
    Includes Correspondence on ILGWU staff's aiding "adopted" Italian children.
  - Joint Boards, Boston, Chicago and Cleveland: 1941-61. (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Joint Boards, Los Angeles Cloak and Dress: 1945-57. (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Joint Boards, Los Angeles: 1949. Investigation conducted by special GEB committee. (Box 30, Folder 1)
    Investigation on charges brought against the L.A. Cloak and Dress Jt. Bds., their officers and executive board members of Locals 65, 84, 96, and 97 by a group of members.
  - Joint Boards, Miami, Montreal, 1955-199. (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Joint Boards, N.Y. Cloak and Dress, 1938-1964. (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Joint Board, Philadelphia, Southern Regional Office, 1941-1960. (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - K., 1948-1956. (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Kennedy, John F., 1960-1961. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - L: Gen. Correspondence., 1941-1951. (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - L: Gen. Correspondence., 1952-1964. (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - La Giustizia, Rome., 1946-1948 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - La Guardia, Fiorello H.: 1934-June 1937., 1934-1937 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - La Guardia, Fiorello H.: July 1937-1940, 1947., 1937-1947 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - La Guardia Memorial House., 1957-1961 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Legislation. Appeals to Government officials on pending legislation., 1939-1942 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Legislation, 1943-1961. (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Lehman, Herbert H., 1939-1940. (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Leonardo Da Vinci Art School, 1939-1941. (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Letters of Recommendation, 1944-1945. (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Liberal Party, 1948-1964. (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Locals 10, 22, 35, and 48, 1940-1964. (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Locals 60, 62, 80, 1940-1959. (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Locals 91, 98, 155, 1947-1961. (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Locals: (n.d.). By-laws, rules and regulations of various locals. (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Local Managers' Conferences. Minutes., 1940-1949 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Local Managers' Conferences, 1950-1952. (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Local Managers' Conferences, 1953-1954. (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Local Managers' Conferences, 1955-1961. (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Lombardo, Ivan Matteo, 1946-191. (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Luncheons, Giuseppe Alessi: Feb. 1957. (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Luncheons, Carmelo Iandoli and Peter Li Causi: July 1959. (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Luncheons, Italian Delegation to the UN 15th General Assembly., 1960 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    Oct. 1960. (Cancelled)
  - Luncheons, Herbert L. Matthews., 1942 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    July 1942.
  - Luncheons, Egidio Ortona., 1960 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    Dec. 1960.
  - Luncheons, Giulio Pastore., 1955 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    Dec. 1955.
  - Luncheons, Matthew Woll., 1955 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    Jan. 1955.
  - Luncheons, Matthew Woll., 1955 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Giuseppe Lupis, 1935-1959. (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - M: Gen. Correspondence, 1938-1950. (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - M: Gen. Correspondence, 1951-1965. (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Madison Square Garden Rally., 1946 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    June 1946. Rally to demonstrate for a just and equitable peace for Italy.
  - Madison Square Garden Rally., 1946 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    June 1946.
  - Marcantonio, Vito., 1934-1941 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    Includes Correspondence re campaigns.
  - Marcantonio, Vito., 1936-1940 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    Printed material by Marcantonio or about him.
  - Marshall Plan Committee., 1948 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Matteotti, Matteo., 1945-1956 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    Includes ltrs. from Matteotti (secretary), PSLI on difficulties of reorganization of new party and labor movement.
  - Mayor's Advisory Committee on Puerto Rico., 1949-1951 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Mazzini, Giuseppe, Bust., 1956-1964 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Mazzini, Giuseppe, Society. (Italy), 1941-1947 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Minutes of IALC Meetings., 1945-1959 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    (Incomplete)
  - Minutes of IALC Meetings., 1960-1964 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Modigliani, Giuseppe E. Correspondence., 1934-1935 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    I.c.w. Pietro Nenni and Union officers on Modigliani's visit to the U.S. as guest of the ILGWU; collection of money for Modigliani Fund for Italian anti-Fascist movement.
  - Modigliani, Giuseppe E. Correspondence., 1936-1938 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    Cont'd. Correspondence on aid to Italian anti-Fascist movement; activities of American Labor Party.
  - Modigliani, Giuseppe E. Correspondence., 1939-1940 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    Includes Correspondence on Italian anti-Semitic laws and Italian Jewish refugees and Socialist refugees in France.
  - Modigliani, Giuseppe E. Correspondence., 1941 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    Cont'd. Correspondence on aiding refugees in southern France and re visas to enter the United States.
  - Modigliani, Giuseppe E. Correspondence., 1942-1948 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    Includes reports from Modigliani on the Italian situation soon after his arrival in Rome, 1944-45.
  - Modigliani, Giuseppe E. Center for the Study of Socialism and the Italian Labor Movement., 1951-1958 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    I.c.w. Vera Modigliani.
  - Montana, Giovanni B. (Vanni)., 1947-1953 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Montana, Giovanni B. (Vanni)., 1958-1964 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    Includes 1954 trip by Union members to Italy.
  - Mutual Security Agency, Special Mission to Italy for Economic Cooperation., 1950-1955 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    Correspondence with Enzo Grassi.
  - N: Gen. Correspondence., 1934-1965 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Natarelli, Patsy. Local 89 officer on trip to Italy., 1950 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Nenni, Pietro. Correspondence., 1934-1937 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    Correspondence on aiding Italian Socialist Party (Partito Socialista Italiana) and Italian refugees in France; Modigliani's visit to U.S. 1934; situation in Spain, 1937.
  - Nenni, Pietro. Correspondence., 1938-1939 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    Includes ltrs. and reports on Spanish and Italian situations.
  - Nenni, Pietro., 1940-1947 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - New York State Federation of Labor., 1943-1952 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    Includes Local resolutions submitted to State conventions.
  - O: Gen. Correspondence., 1947-1964 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - "Open City" showing: May 1946. Invitations for a reception and special showing of film. (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Organization for Rehabilitation Through Training in Industry and Agriculture (ORT)., 1942 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    Mar. 1942. Correspondence re Music Festival of Allied Nations.
  - P: Gen. Correspondence, 1945-1964. (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Pacciardi, Randolfo, 1950-1965. (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Pastors, Giulio. (Substantial) Correspondence., 1949-1952 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    Correspondence when he was general secretary of Italian Confederation of Workers Unions (CISL). Includes ltr. to the executive committee of Communist-dominated unions on CISL policies, 1949.
  - Pastore, Giulio. Correspondence., 1953-1955 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    Correspondence on labor and political activities in Italy, requests for aid.
  - Pastore, Giulio, 1956-1957. (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Pastore, Giulio, 1958-1960. (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Poletti, Charles, 1936-1940. (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Politics, 1934-1952. (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Pope, Generoso, 1947-1948. (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Pozzallo, Italy. Correspondence., 1949 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    Correspondence re packages of medicine sent to this town.
  - Press Releases. (Local 89 and IALC), 1939-1940 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Press Releases, 1942-1943. (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Press Releases, 1948 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Press Releases, 1949-1952. (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Press Releases, 1953-1964. (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Procopio, Joseph, 1949-1965. (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Subject Files, R. (Box 38)
  - R: Gen. Correspondence, 1946-195. (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Radio, "Voice of Local 89." Includes other broadcast matters., 1942-1950 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Rank and File Groups, Local 89, 1939-1947. (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Recommendations, Letters of, 1939-1941. (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Recommendations, Letters of, 1942-1949. (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Recommendations, Letters of, 1950-1952. (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Recommendations, Letters of, 1953-1954. (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Relief Drive for Italy, 1946 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Reports, General, Local 89., 1934-1946 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    Includes census of membership, Committee on Law, statements, Local activities.
  - Reports, Financial, Local 89, 1948-1949. (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Reports, Financial, 1950-1951. (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Reports, Financial, 1952-1953. (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Reports, Financial, 1954-1955. (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Reports, Financial, 1957-1958. (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Reports, Financial, 1959-1960 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    1959-June 1960.
  - Reports, Financial, 1960-1961 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    July 1960-61.
  - Romita, Giuseppe., 1956-1957 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Romualdi, Serafino., 1944-1961 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    Includes Correspondence on Italian political situation.
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D.., 1936-1947 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    Includes election Correspondence, birthday balls, FDR ltr. thanking American Labor Party for their support in 1936 election.
  - Roosevelt Institute (Vocational School for Orphans), Palermo, Italy (Instituto di Arti E Mestiere Franklin D. Roosevelt)., 1945- 1948 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Roosevelt Institute, 1949-1950 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    1949-July 1950.
  - Roosevelt Institute, 1950-1951 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    Sept. 1950-51.
  - Roosevelt Institute., 1952-1953 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Roosevelt Institute., 1954-1955 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Roosevelt Institute., 1956-1957 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Roosevelt Institute., 1958-1959 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    1958-May 1959.
  - Roosevelt Institute., 1959-1960 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    June 1959-60.
  - Roosevelt Institute., 1961-1963 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Roosevelt Institute., 1964-1965 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Roosevelt Plaque., 1934 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    March 1934. Presented by Local 89.
  - S: Gen. Correspondence, 1947-1951. (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - S: Gen. Correspondence, 1953-1964. (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Saragat, Giuseppe. Correspondence., 1946-1948 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    Correspondence on Italian labor and political matters.
  - Saragat, Giuseppe, 1949-1965. (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Saragat, Giuseppe, 1947 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Dinner in honor of Saragat and Matteo Matteotti. (Box 43, Folder 6)
    Includes their speeches and that of Adolph A. Berle, Jr.
  - Scelba, Mario., 1949-1961 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Scelba, Mario. Dinner in honor of Mario Scelba and Gaetano Martino., 1955 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Selective Service, 1951 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Sforza, Count Carlo, 1947-1950. (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Silone, Ignazio. Dispute between Antonini and Silone after Silone returned to Italy., 1945 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Simonini, Alberto, 1948-1949. (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Simonini, Alberto, 1950-190. (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Social Democratic Party, Italian (Partito Socialista Democratico Italiano), 1952-1964. (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Socialist Party, Italian (Partito Socialista Italiano), 1946-198. (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Socialist Party, United (Partito Socialista Unitario), 1950-1951. (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Socialist Party of Italian Workers (Partito Socialista dei Lavoratori Italiani)., 1947-1951 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    1947-Apr. 1948, 1951.
  - Socialist Party of Italian Workers (Partito Socialista dei Lavoratori Italiani)., 1948 (Box 44, Folder 8)
    May 1948.
  - Sons of Italy Grand Lodge (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Sons of Italy, 1937-1961. (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Spataro, Giuseppe, 1951-1953. (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Speeches, Statements and Articles, 1941-1955. (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Stratiesky, Barbara, 1955-1959. (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Strike of 1936 by N.Y. Dress and Waistmakers. (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - T: Gen. Correspondence., 1946-1955 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Tamburino, Toto., 1951-1958 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Terracini, Umberto. Antonini ltr. to Terracini., 1947 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    re ltr. concerning aid to Social Democrats that was stolen from Saragat.
  - Thomas, Norman., 1949-1955 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Trade-Unions Committee for Democratic Education and Relief for Workers (Comitato Sindacale di Educazione Democratica and di Assistenza ai Lavoratori), Italy., 1945-1947 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Tresca, Carlo., 1938-1947 (Box 45, Folder 10)
    I.c.w. Tresca, 1939-42 and Tresca Memorial Committee, 1947.
  - Tresca, Carlo, Institute., 1949-1951 (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Tresca, Carlo., 1943 (Box 45, Folder 12)
    Jan. 1943. Newspaper clippings on his assassination and probe into his death.
  - Trieste. Correspondence on status of Trieste., 1948-1964 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Trieste, Chamber of Labor (Camera Confederale del Lavoro)., 1952-1964 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Trieste. Delegates Giuseppe Dulci and Attilio Coen visit on behalf of the labor movement of Trieste., 1949 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Trips Abroad, Brussels and France., 1935 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    Delegate to Italian Labor and Socialist Congress Against War.
  - Trips Abroad, Italy., 1946 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    Dealing with peace terms for Italy; Includes John Gelo trip.
  - Trips Abroad, Italy., 1946 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Trips Abroad, Italy., 1948 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    Includes list of disbursements for orphanages and institutions.
  - Trips Abroad, Italy., 1951 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    Delegate to Second Congress of the International Confederation of Free Trade Unions to survey the political and labor movement and Union relief program.
  - Trips Abroad, Italy and Israel., 1956 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    Goodwill tour to Italy; trip to Israel for dedication of the Luigi Antonini Stadium, Haifa.
  - Trips Abroad, Italy., 1957-1961 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    Includes E. Howard Molisani's report.
  - Trips Abroad, South America. Newspaper clippings., 1939 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    March 20-30, 1939. American Labor Party delegate to Conference of the Pan-American Congress of Democracies, Montevideo, Uruguay.
  - Trips Abroad, South America, 1939 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Trips Abroad, South America. Newspaper clippings., 1939 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Trips Abroad, South America, 1939 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Truman, Harry S, 1945-1954. (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - U: Gen. Correspondence, 1942-1960. (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Unions, 1936-1964. (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Unions, Textile Workers Union of America; 1946-61. (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Unions, Italy, 1944-1948. (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - United Nations., 1945 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    April 1945. Correspondence, IALC resolution on having Italy participate at the San Francisco conference of the United Nations.
  - U.S. Government Officials. Misc. matters. (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - V: Gen. Correspondence, 1943-1960. (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Vacirca, Vincenzo, 1948-1950. (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Valiani, Leo, 1946 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Vampa, Valeria, 1948-1951. (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Voice of 89 League, 1946-1947. (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - W: Gen. Correspondence., 1941-1961. (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Wagner, Robert F., Jr., 1953-1963. (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Welfare Dept., City of N.Y., 1939-1951 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    Correspondence with Edward Corsi.
  - Women's Trade Union League., 1939-1954 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Workers School (Casa per la Formazione dei Lavoratori)., 1960 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    Includes Correspondence re World's Fair, 1939.
  - Z: Gen. Correspondence., 1947-1961 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Zavaroni, Enzo., 1948-1959 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Letters to Antonini, many to be aired on radio, "Voice of Local 89." (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Printed Material: 1930's. Includes The Word of the Dressmakers. (Box 49, Folder 9)
- Series III. Speeches, 1935-1948.
  - Luigi Antonini speeches for radio series over WEVD, "Voice of Local 89.", 1935-1964 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    1935-July 13, 1964.
  - Speeches: 1935-Feb. 1937., 1935-1937 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Speeches: Mar. 1937-June 1938., 1937-1938 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Speeches: July 1938-Oct. 1939., 1938-1939 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Speeches: Nov. 1939-1940. (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Speeches: Jan.-Dec. 1941. (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Speeches: Jan.-Dec. 1942. (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Speeches: Jan. -Dec. 1943. (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Speeches: Jan. 1944-Feb. 1945., 1944-1945 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Speeches: Mar, 1945-Apr. 1946., 1945-1946 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Speeches: 1946-Dec. 1947., 1946-1947 (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Speeches: Jan, 1948-May 1949., 1948-1949 (Box 60, Folder 1)